I've been a critical care EMT for the past seven years in Suffolk County, New York.
لقد عملت كفني طوارئ للحالات الحرجة طوال السبع سنوات السابقة في ضاحية سافلوك نيويورك
I've been a first responder in a number of incidents
كنت اول المجيبين في عديد من الحوادث
ranging from car accidents to Hurricane Sandy.
تتراوح من حوادث السيارات الي العواصف الرملية
If you are like most people, death might be
لو كنت مثل معظم الناس, ربما يكون الموت
one of your greatest fears.
واحد من اعظم مخاوفك
Some of us will see it coming.
بعضنا سيراه قادماً
Some of us won't.
و بعضنا لن يراه
There is a little-known documented medical term
هناك مصطلح طبي معروف و موثق غير معروف
called impending doom.
يدعي الموث الوشيك
It's almost a symptom.
و هو بالكاد عرض
As a medical provider, I'm trained to respond
كمزود طبي, انا مدرب للاستجابة
to this symptom like any other,
لهذا العرض كاي عرض اخر
so when a patient having a heart attack looks at me
لذا عندما ينظر الي مريض عنده ازمة قلبية مريض
and says, "I'm going to die today,"
و يقول " سأموت اليوم "
we are trained to reevaluate the patient's condition.
نحن مدربون علي اعادة تقييم حالة المريض
Throughout my career, I have responded
خلال مهنتي,استجبت
to a number of incidents where the patient
لعدد من الحالات حيث كان المريض
had minutes left to live
لديه فقط دقائق علي الحياة
and there was nothing I could do for them.
و لم يكن هناك شئ يمكن ان افعله لهم
With this, I was faced with a dilemma:
مع هذا الامر, كنت اواجه معضلة
Do I tell the dying that they are about to face death,
هل اخبر المقبل علي الموت انه اقترب من مواجهة الموت
or do I lie to them to comfort them?
ام اكذب عليهم لاريحهم ؟
Early in my career, I faced this dilemma
في بداية مهنتي, واجهت هذة المعضلة
by simply lying.
بالكذب ببساطة
I was afraid.
كنت خائفا
I was afraid if I told them the truth,
كنت خائفا لو اخبرتهم الحقيقة
that they would die in terror, in fear,
انهم سيموتون في رهبة في خوف
just grasping for those last moments of life.
متمسكين باخر لحظات في الحياة
That all changed with one incident.
و الذي تغير بحادثة واحدة
Five years ago, I responded to a motorcycle accident.
منذ خمس سنوات استجبت لحادثة دراجة نارية
The rider had suffered critical, critical injuries.
السائق كان يعاني من جراح حرجة جدا
As I assessed him, I realized that there was nothing
و بينما اقيم حالته ادركت انه لا يوجد شئ
that could be done for him,
استطيع فعله له
and like so many other cases, he looked me in the eye
و كحالات كثيرة اخري, نظر في عيني
and asked that question: "Am I going to die?"
و سألني هذا السؤال:"هل سأموت؟"
In that moment, I decided to do something different.
في هذة اللحظة قررت ان افعل شئ مختلف
I decided to tell him the truth.
قررت ان اخبره الحقيقة
I decided to tell him that he was going to die
قررت ان اخبره انه سيموت
and that there was nothing I could do for him.
و انه لا يوجد ما استطيع فعله له
He simply laid back and had a look
هو ببساطة رجع للخلف و كانت له نظرة
of acceptance on his face.
قبول علي وجهة
He was not met with that terror or fear
لم يواجة هذة الرهبة او الرعب
that I thought he would be.
التي كنت اعتقد انه سيواجة
He simply laid there, and as I looked into his eyes,
هو ببساطة رجع للخلف و بينما انظر في عينيه
I saw inner peace and acceptance.
رأيت سلام داخلي و قبول
From that moment forward, I decided
من هدة اللحظة قررت
it was not my place to comfort the dying with my lies.
ليس من حقي ان اريح المقبلين علي الموت بالاكاذيب
Having responded to many cases since then
و قد استجبت للعديد من الحالات من وقتها
where patients were in their last moments
حيث كان المرضي في اخر لحظاتهم
and there was nothing I could do for them,
و لم يكن هناك ما استطيع فعله لهم
in almost every case,
تقريبا في كل الحالات
they have all had the same reaction to the truth,
كان لهم جميعا نفس رد الفعل تجاة الحقيقة
of inner peace and acceptance.
من السلام الداخلي و القبول
In fact, there are three patterns
في الواقع هناك ثلاث انماط
I have observed in all these cases.
لاحظتها في كل هذة الحالات
The first pattern always kind of shocked me.
اول نمط دائما ما كان يصدمني
Regardless of religious belief or cultural background,
بغض النظر عن الاعتقادات الدينية أو الخلفية الثقافية
there's a need for forgiveness.
هناك حاجة للغفران
Whether they call it sin
سواء يسمونها خطايا
or they simply say they have a regret,
او ببساطة يقولون انهم نادمون
their guilt is universal.
ذنبهم عام
I had once cared for an elderly gentleman
اهتممت مره برجل كبير في السن
who was having a massive heart attack.
و الذي كان لديه ازمة قلبية كبيرة
As I prepared myself and my equipment
و بينما اجهز نفسي و معداتي
for his imminent cardiac arrest,
لازمته القلبية الوشيكة
I began to tell the patient of his imminent demise.
بدأت اخبار المريض بموته الوشيك
He already knew by my tone of voice and body language.
هو عرف من نبرة صوتي و لغة الجسد
As I placed the defibrillator pads on his chest,
و بينما اضع جهاز الصدمة الكهربائية علي صدره
prepping for what was going to happen,
و استعد لما سيحدث
he looked me in the eye and said,
نظر في عيني و قال
"I wish I had spent more time with my children and grandchildren
"اتمني لو انني امضيت وقت اكثر مع اولادي و احفادي"
instead of being selfish with my time."
بدلاً من ان اكون اناني في وقتي
Faced with imminent death,
عندما واجة الموت الوشيك
all he wanted was forgiveness.
كل ما اراده هو الغفران
The second pattern I observe
النمط الثاني الذي لاحظته
is the need for remembrance.
هو الحاجة للتذكر
Whether it was to be remembered in my thoughts
سواء ان يُذكر في افكاري
or their loved ones', they needed to feel
او من احبهم , ارادوا ان يشعروا
that they would be living on.
انهم سيظلوا احياء
There's a need for immortality
هناك حاجة للابدية
within the hearts and thoughts of their loved ones,
في قلوب و افكار من احبوهم
myself, my crew, or anyone around.
انا و طاقمي و اي احد حولهم
Countless times, I have had a patient look me in the eyes
مرات لا تحصي اجد مريض ينظر في عيني
and say, "Will you remember me?"
و يقول ,"هل ستتذكرني ؟"
The final pattern I observe
اخر نمط شاهدته
always touched me the deepest, to the soul.
دائما ما كان يأثر عميقا في روحي
The dying need to know that their life had meaning.
المقبلين علي الموت يريدون ان يعرفوا ان حياتهم كان لها معني
They need to know that they did not waste their life
يريدون انا يعرفوا انهم لم يضيعوا حياتهم
on meaningless tasks.
في مهام بلا معني
This came to me very, very early in my career.
هذا اتي مبكرا جدا في مهنتي
I had responded to a call.
استجبت لحالة
There was a female in her late 50s
كانت امرأة في أخر الخمسينات من عمرها
severely pinned within a vehicle.
حوصرت بشدة داخل سيارة
She had been t-boned at a high rate of speed,
صدمت بجانب السيارة بسرعة عالية
critical, critical condition.
حالة حرجة جدا
As the fire department worked to remove her from the car,
بينما يعمل الاطفائيين لاخراجها من السيارة
I climbed in to begin to render care.
انا دخلت لابدأ في تقديم الرعاية
As we talked, she had said to me,
و بينما نتكلم, قالت لي
"There was so much more I wanted to do with my life."
كان هناك الكثير من الاشياء التي اردت فعلها في حياتي
She had felt she had not left her mark on this Earth.
شعرت انها لم تترك علامتها في هذة الارض
As we talked further, it would turn out
و لما تكلمنا اكثر اتضح انها
that she was a mother of two adopted children
ام لابنين بالتبني
who were both on their way to medical school.
و الذين كانا في طريقهم الي كلية الطب
Because of her, two children
بسببها هي, طفلين
had a chance they never would have had otherwise
اصبح لديهم فرصة لم تكن لتتاح لهم لولاها
and would go on to save lives in the medical field
و سيتمكنون من انقاذ ارواح في مجال الطب
as medical doctors.
كاطباء
It would end up taking 45 minutes
انتهي الامر في 45 دقيقة
to free her from the vehicle.
لاخراجها من السيارة
However, she perished prior to freeing her.
مع ذلك, وافتها المنية قبل تحريرها
I believed what you saw in the movies:
اعتقد ان ما تراه في الافلام
when you're in those last moments
عندما تكون في اخر اللحظات هذة
that it's strictly terror, fear.
انه هلع و خوف
I have come to realize, regardless of the circumstance,
ادركت انه بغض النظر عن الظروف
it's generally met with peace and acceptance,
انه عامة يقابل بسلام و قبول
that it's the littlest things, the littlest moments,
انه تلك الاشياء الصغيرة اللحظات الصغيرة
the littlest things you brought into the world
الاشياء الصغيرة التي احضرتها للعالم
that give you peace in those final moments.
هي التي تمنحك السلام في هذة اللحظات الاخيرة
Thank you.
شكرا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)